Here they grow again.
Gremlins 2: The New Batch is a comedy, horror,
fantasy film directed by Joe Dante.
Young sweethearts Billy and Kate move to the Big Apple, land jobs in a high-tech
office park and soon reunite with the friendly and lovable Gizmo.
But a series of accidents creates a whole new generation of Gremlins.
The situation worsens when the devilish green creatures invade a top-secret laboratory and
develop genetically altered powers, making them even harder to destroy!
Billy Peltzer, played by Zach Galligan.
Kate Beringer, played by Phoebe Cates.
Daniel Clamp, played by John Glover.
Grandpa Fred, played by Robert Prosky.
Forster, played by Robert Picardo.
Doctor Catheter, played by Christopher Lee.
Gremlins 2: The New Batch is a 1990 American comedy horror
film and the sequel to Gremlins (1984).
It was directed by Joe Dante, written by Charles S.
Haas and features creature designs by Rick Baker.
Zach Galligan and Phoebe Cates reprise their roles from the first film, with John
Glover, Robert Prosky, Robert Picardo and Christopher Lee joining the cast.
It continues the story of Billy Peltzer and the mogwai Gizmo, who spawns more of his kind when wet that
eventually become imp-like monsters and proceed to wreak havoc within a skyscraper in New York City.
The film heavily parodies its predecessor, with more
cartoonish elements and less horror.
There are a number of parodies of other forms of popular culture, including the Rambo
franchise, The Wizard of Oz, Marathon Man and The Phantom of the Opera.
It was theatrically released on June 15, 1990, and
received generally positive reviews.
It grossed $42 million on a budget of $30–50 million.
Since its release, it has developed a cult following.
A third film is set for release on November 19, 2027.
The film explores themes of dying and death, new york
city, monster, mutation, cleverness.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.